# **Joris Ooms**

### FREELANCE UI DEVELOPER

0496 78 72 76 — hello at cupofcode dot be — cupofcode.be — jorisooms.be

I am a full stack developer with over 10 years of direct experience across multiple sectors, ranging from advertising and start-up outfits to SME's and multi-nationals. I specialize in building reliable, well-tested applications and interactive websites.

My specialty skillset and interests lie in TypeScript development with modern HTML, CSS and React on the front-end and Node.js on the back-end. Beyond this, I retain a broad interest in general software development and am equally well-versed in technologies such as, for example, Ruby on Rails, Wordpress or Elm. I am used to working with the Atlassian stack (Jira, Confluence, ...) in agile environments, using scrum methodologies.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### CONSULTANCY WORK

In my consultancy work, I focus on TypeScript and React development while making extensive use of the JavaScript ecosystem.

## Pelckmans Uitgevers - Senior React developer

01.2022 - 07.2024

Pelckmans Uitgevers is one of the leading publishing houses in Belgium. Since 2022 I have worked on a complete migration of their "Pelckmans Portaal" project from Angular JS to React. The public portal is where students and teachers can access study materials, exercises and tests. The completed migration went live in January 2024 without issues.

#### Flow Pilots - Lead React developer

08.2021 - 12.2021

Flow Pilots reached out to me when their client EuroControl asked them to build an application in React, which FP had no experience in. Over the course of six months, I built the front-end for a "visitor management portal", where EuroControl employees could manage meetings, keep track of visitors, issue and retract badges, etc. The application was a modern React application working against a .NET backend.

## Pelckmans Uitgevers - Senior full stack developer

02.2019 - 07.2021

Pelckmans Uitgevers is one of the leading publishing houses in Belgium. On the one hand, I work on the public portal for students and teachers, where they can access their schoolbooks, exercises, and tests. On the other hand, I work on the "digibook" application, where we render interactive versions of the books for use in classrooms.

### IxorTalk / Udini / Zyzo – Senior React developer

10.2018 - 02.2019

Udini is an IoT platform for smart buildings. I worked on the customer dashboard where users can create organisations and roles, invite users, and create smart flows for their digital badges.

Zyzo is a hard- and software platform aimed at the elderly and their families. My work here mainly consists of code reviews, technical discussions and mentoring the other developers on the team.

Assorted research projects for IxorThink, the AI branch of Ixor.

Spott teamed up with IxorThink to build a new version of their video-tagging software. I built the front-end, connecting video to object-tracking and deep learning algorithms.

Ixor aims to join machine learning and pathology research in their Pathology Portal. I developed the front-end for this portal, connecting bone-marrow scans to machine learning algorithms.

I mentored a junior developer who would later assume responsibility for these projects.

Public trading platform for the banking industry, via lxor.

Ixor partnered with The Glue to build a public trading platform for the banking industry. I worked on-site with a team of five developers to build a complex single-page application for a major Belgian bank. As the technical frontend lead, it was my responsibility to make architectural decisions, review code and mentor the other developers.

Video streaming and logging platform for internal use.

EVS is widely regarded as the leading player in live video technology. As the lead UI developer, I worked together with developers from Ixor and EVS to convert their desktop application to a flexible, scalable web application. I wrote code, took all decisions regarding architecture, and mentored other developers. This project was partly remote in Liège.

Administrative platform for Antwerp local police.

I worked as a full stack developer at Digipolis to build a digital platform to be used in police cars while on the road. I wrote a lot of React code but also worked on the backend side in NodeJS and Elixir.

#### 2. Full-time employment

SocialExpress offers social media analytics for data-driven marketers. I helped developed the next version of their product using AngularJS, Sass and NodeJS. A proof of concept with first steps in React was also built. SocialExpress has since been acquired by Bynder.

HTML, CSS, and JS development according to web-standards, while making use of (at the time) cutting edge technologies. Worked for clients such as: Telenet, Bancontact/Mister Cash, Toerisme Vlaanderen, Toerisme Provincie Antwerpen, Gimv, among many others.

# 3. ASSORTED FREELANCE DEVELOPMENT

For all projects described below, I developed both the front-end and back-end (if applicable).

Mainsquare Festival – mainsquarefestival.fr

Website for the French Mainsquare Festival in Arras. As .madeforscreen, commissioned by LiveNation. 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020 editions.

Ik sorteer! — iksorteer.be

Website with information on sorting household waste for OVAM. Commissioned by DickyTall.

PuurSchlager - puurschlager.be

Website for the schlager music festival in Puurs. Commissioned by Artillerie.

Mitsubishi Fuso Truck Explorer — explore.fusotrucks.be

Truck explorer for Mitsubishi Fuso trucks. Commissioned by Omakase.

Triamant Haspengouw - haspengouwsgeluk.be

Campaign website for Triamant, a company which focuses on homes for the elderly. Commissioned by Omakase.

Antilliaanse Feesten – antilliaansefeesten.be

Website for the largest Carribean festival in the world. Commissioned by Flexid / Omakase.

Thermaflex — thermaflex.com

Company website for Thermaflex, a leading solution provider of special pipes and insulation systems made from environmentally friendly polyolefins. Commissioned by Omakase.

# **SKILLSET**

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript / TypeScript
- React
- Jest, React Testing Library
- Node.js
- MongoDB

# **EDUCATION**

2009 – 2011 Interactive Multimedia Design (Bachelor's degree) Lessius Hogeschool, Mechelen

## **LANGUAGES**

Dutch, English